all right so
let's talk about failure how can we try
to fail at creating community
if we just really wanted to fail at it
like what is that
is it the producers or they try to put
on a failed
nazi musical and ends up being a success
but they need it to be a failure
that was i just feel like i need to
throw it here that's a little bit what i
thought the trump presidency was in the
beginning i was like waiting for him to
be like you're kidding me right you guys
actually elected me and like step away i
thought that's what happened i thought
he was like
this is weird that this is happening
but but that aside no we might talk
about trump
um if we wanted to fail at creating an
intentional community what would we do
to be absolutely miserable at it
i think um a lot of rules very strict
rules i get to control everything
that i think would be a great no one
which would be like double failure
because i both really don't like
you'd have to micromanage everyone and
they wouldn't be happy so
i wouldn't be happy and they wouldn't be
happy it'd be great
okay so too many rules
one of the first things that came to my
mind uh reading the topic
uh was just the the feeling that people
get
from the the community like good good
communities good relationships people
kind of get a sense of being energized
by them uh they get they get recharged
they come out of it feeling you know
kind of more alive and more excited and
more ready to go take on the world
versus anything that they kind of have
to sink energy into
and leaves them feeling drained or like
it's a chore
or just one more obligation on top of
the 15 other obligations that they have
in any given day or week
very different you know essential
quality there
so it sounds a little bit like you're
saying that a good
thing is for people to feel uplifted by
interactions so if you were to fail at
that
you would make people feel worse in some
way from
interactions yeah it's really an outcome
measure on the tail end
of you know did you succeed or fail and
i think that a
a lot of that what people would say is
success or failures probably correlated
with that how did it make me feel uh
kind of thing
i think promising big things they're not
delivering like here's and this kind of
goes to what james was saying like the
um
here's my vision for a community but you
make it like you do all the work
you get all the people like you put all
of your energy into it but for my vision
which is like the opposite of what
to fail
um one of the things that comes to mind
is participation
not giving people enough avenues to
participate
so if you have too large of a
personality
that is kind of like you need some
leadership in my opinion
but someone who is the leadership
they're like a control freak and they
can't take their hands off of things
uh when new people show up you need ways
for them to say
hey yeah we've got something for you to
do people want to feel
like they're participating that's a part
of feeling valuable if i say
well you can just sit around because i
have nothing for you
that ability to delegate um even if it's
you know big things or small things or
whatever um
avenues for participation is uh
comes to mind
and i might extend that participation
out into sense of ownership
kind of even stronger that feeling of oh
you know i
i own this i made this
uh i had a hand in creating this
yeah yeah
um so the participation would be a good
thing so the bad thing
i i think yeah someone having
being a micromanaging personality they
can't take their hands off of things
um they're too controlling
that one or a few people in a community
like that
that have power seems like a bad mix
uh the recipe for um
not a good outcome i think with that
no training in what you're doing right
like you go and build this cob house but
like you get no training and will berate
you
and having an assigned task that you're
expected to be good at with no training
as opposed to a a task that does speak
to you right and it's either something
you're you're challenging yourself to
learn and you have mentorship
or something you're already good at and
want to to contribute
having so like like no you're the farmer
daniel from now on you're
you're doing the farm work and if we all
starve it's on you
so we've got too many rules um
situations that
are draining energy uh
we talked about
no avenues for participation and there's
some reasons why that would be good
people want a sense of hey i'm valuable
when i'm here
also zero diversity like all one age
group
all one income level all one thing that
that isn't very clear
that um like if a bunch of rich people
get together and start a community like
wait who's gonna who's gonna take the
compost out not me i'm rich like not me
like having the or or that also goes to
tasks that you like to do fucking
everyone else to listen to you
and yeah i just i really love the
intergenerational part of communities
like only children lord of the flies
that would be
oh they prove you wrong anyway i have a
mixed reaction to that one because it
kind of depends on what level or what
type of community
you're talking about here uh
everybody being the same can be a
powerful spark for people drawing
together
uh and forming you know you think a lot
of you could feel your your
friend group in high school or whatever
like it was likely because you had some
sort of sameness
shared interests shared clubs same you
just felt like the same kind of click
but yeah different scales and different
goals and different health levels
of well are you trying to create a
community that like can
expand to accept anybody in the whole
world well then you absolutely you need
to champion a diversity
uh as a core hallmark of that kind of
community but
um you know communities the
yeah depending on where you land on kind
of the in group out group
and how do you define the boundary of
the community yeah like it's it's
complicated
i love that james because it's like both
ends of the spectrum
either force diversity right like we're
going to try and find people that are so
unrelated how do you even get along or
like the
entire community clones of myself
well would that ever be a nightmare like
i'd have to deal with my own shit
constantly and no one would want to do
what i don't want to do because we don't
want to do the exact same thing
like both ends of them yeah
i feel like you've got a sensitivity to
hardships and ableness
in there for example like
yeah if you had a community of of mostly
uh wealthy people and
some of their ideas required folks to be
able to spend money to go
do a thing you're gonna leave people out
who don't have
extra money to spend um so that might be
like decisions
you're having when you're going into it
um you know i think if i'm thinking of
like more of like an
off-grid community that
uh is gonna be more inclusive
um just having sensitivity
to that there might be situations where
some people might
feel left out um and i'm thinking a
little bit about
ableness like everybody's got people
have different
disabilities and things that they
struggle with
and so yeah like a high inclusive
community
some kind of game b off grid thing
is gonna have to be sensitive to that i
think um
if it's really gonna work and then i've
got like
you know my my if i've got a community
where we play hockey together
like well there are probably
you know um hockey leagues
for folks who are in wheelchairs
etc but that's not every league
um and so yeah you might have to
differentiate like hey we'll
what we're doing there
there was a um short story
i read in in high school and i can't
remember what the name of it is but it
was the idea that
you um for lack of a better word
handicap everyone who isn't
who is like intelligent and strong
and so that they're at the bottom yeah i
know
and uh and like that's kind of whenever
i say i'm making a world for everyone
like that's what they picture and i'm
like no it's the
like you don't stop being intelligent so
that other people feel
more intelligent you but you don't make
people wrong for not being intelligent
like you you work with
people's individual um abilities
and they weave together quite well if
you can honor that but
yeah you need everyone to be i was
thinking of i know people who i kind of
what the name of it is i want to call it
murder ball that's not right at all but
it's
similar harrison it's harrison bergeron
the dysotopian science fiction yeah if
you were
if you were more intelligent they
handicapped you so that everybody was
the same right
yeah there was like something in your
brain that would like
if you were a thinker it would make you
go off if you were strong they had these
weights on you and then also like the
weights fall off i think when the guy
goes
because he was he was super strong but
um there's something in that of like
like if you forced everyone to play
hockey in a wheelchair
the people who are used to being in a
wheelchair could have a much bigger
advantage
than like it's hard to use that right
like it's a hard piece of equipment to
learn to use and now all of a sudden we
all have to use it and yet
there absolutely needs to be space for
everyone to be able to play the
the sports and the hobbies and the stuff
that you want requiring that's again
like the forged diversity
or the everyone's exactly the same both
of those are poison
it's finding the like beautiful magic
in the diversity of like right we're all
different
what do you need to be able to succeed
what do both as an individual and as a
community because they're
the same right that if i can help you
succeed at your highest level
we're going to get you at your highest
level if i have to tell you what that
highest level is right like this is the
bar you have to meet it
and if you're not there then you don't
get to be part of the community
even that would probably work better
than like pretending you can be part of
the community and then not actually
making any kind of accommodation
and just making you feel bad that you
can't keep up to that
yeah i mean you're off-grid type of
community is going to have to be
sensitive to
all sorts of things that
people that take medication people with
allergies
people with diabetes your
your food choices
you're going to have to i guess how
would a community fail
would you fail to take enough of those
things into account
um that's for sure or to take all of
those things to account right to just if
we have four of us were starting a
community i don't know what our dietary
restrictions are but of all the sudden
for every meal we needed to make sure
there was a vegan option a gluten-free
option a diabetic option is salt
you know what i mean when like we don't
know if those people are included here
it's different if somebody
does have an allergy i know when we have
common dinners or certain foods we do
not include in the common dinners
because there's people with anaphylactic
allergies to it
um and yet you can cook in your own
house with that right but to say okay
well anyone who has an anaphylactic
allergy to anything we're not going to
cook with it we're not going to eat
anything
i'll toss out uh money uh just as a
huge general category of ways to fail
there are a lot of different ways
uh that you can fail relating to money
um requiring it needing it setting it up
so that it's the backbone of the
community and the community needs the
flow of money to
survive it can failure through
kind of the corruption uh of that
uh is one that i'll all you know sort of
point in the direction
of a lot of institutions uh you know
churches
uh or other you know communities that
have set themselves up with a building
and staff and all of these ongoing fixed
expenses
uh that then you know kind of is a
competing
um competing threat that competes with
you know whatever the
you know maybe original point of the
community was
uh and turns that into a um
a bad um incentive landscape a lot of
times
yeah i mean corruption can come into uh
you're talking about monetary needs and
funding needs and when you said
corruption i was like oh yeah well that
could pop up
in many different areas
um so yeah one way to fail is to have
some corruption in there one way to fail
is to not i would think
let's see i didn't come into this
discussion
thinking a lot ahead of time about this
but
you know you could fail by not having
good ways to
vet people to keep out corruption
i mean if someone's enough of a
sociopath you might
never be able to like stop them from you
know
getting in but um
you could completely fail to have ways
to to vet people
i think that's um like ignoring humanity
ignoring what humanity is either with
like
um ignoring that we have the pareto
distribution there's gonna be people who
contribute more and people who should be
less and so like making that a mandatory
everyone contributes the same across the
board the exact same way
um or financially right it's it's
this amount of money in which can work
or not but like not having those things
written out not
like there's no sociopaths in the world
like i'm not even gonna think about that
there's not
like no one no everyone is perfect and
so
not owning that humanity is we maybe
have some issues including
not having conflict resolution not
allowing conflict
so it's all simmering under the surface
and not having a way
to deal with that a way to be like okay
how do you bring
issues to light in a way that's
respectful and not letting it get to
that boiling point
the lack the lack of conflict resolution
mechanisms
and norms that by itself
can trigger a failure no matter how good
you are at
screening or onboarding or interviewing
people
the input side
juan i'd love to hear your ideas i
wasn't quite able to read your um
i skimmed it but i wasn't able to read
your article but i'd love to hear how
how you would fail miserably
oh we can't hear you yes now
no no okay so
um listening all of you i i was thinking
a little bit about
my relation to failure in general
so first of all
[Music]
i have to say that i have a very good
relation
to failure for me
it is a kind of exception i
i see a standard the standard a routine
process which is like everybody
like it is a kind of
accepted common sense to do this in this
way
and uh most of the time something is
labeled failure
uh when it doesn't work like it was
before so it is a kind of exception
but um i see this
failure or this field of failures
as the only area of innovation
and related to the topic community
for me is a free
speech place
an area for trying
something and failing is a very
important part of community life
so my relation to failure is
very
that's positive one of the biggest ways
we would fail is to not allow failure
not allow a space to allow that not try
new things and
remain stagnant yeah that's pretty good
that's that's helpful
safe to fail has been the phrase that
i've heard and used a lot for that and
not making it
safe to fail
yeah we have a saint in our community
which is safe enough to try
and that of course means that we're
trying it see if it
fails or not right like you're not gonna
know we can think about it all we want
but
is it safe enough to try right like
drinking bleach not safe enough to try
but using this new product trying this
new system
safe enough to try which means there's
an option to fail
are they like safe enough to fail or
what was the one what it wasn't safe it
was what was it james
are safe to fail and then safe to try
yeah well uh so we got a pretty good
list going
um i really like that last point another
one
that i can think of is
from what i can tell you need a balance
between
um being having spaces where
you're listening you're doing maybe like
a community check-ins um
relational check-ins healing types of
spaces
and kind of like the the doing types of
spaces where
we've got to you know we've got some
practical
logistical uh things that just need to
be done
carpentry type of stuff you know the
roof has a leak
somebody's got to fix it or whatever um
i think you could fail by being way too
far
on one end of those um i think
my personal experience is that
uh places i've been in tend to go too
far into the doing it's like what are we
doing here let's just
do with our hands and move around and do
everything and very little
relational check-in how is everybody is
everybody getting their needs met
and you know etc that whole type of
thing
so you need to be balanced with with
there i think you can fail
by being way too far on either one of
those
yeah being and doing
as one way i've heard of that i've i've
also heard the metaphor
of the balance of face to face
and shoulder to shoulder in terms of
shoulder shoulder you're working on
something
uh together face to face here you know
each other
so having a culture where you say hey
we've been getting a lot
done but let's do uh you know a two-hour
campfire where we
check in uh stuff like that you could
really fail i think if you left that out
you'd have
people working alongside one another
you could go for weeks or months like
this um
but if you don't have um
mechanisms i usually think of leadership
but
hey at the least if you don't have
mechanisms for people to pause and have
ways to check in and
and have conversations like that
you're going to end up i don't know
i wouldn't want to participate in
especially some kind of off-grid
community where we weren't
doing that on a regular basis
also having um the community like only
having common space having nowhere you
can retreat to
to be by yourself or to get that that
alone time
or having only alone time because that's
clearly not a community
uh bad acoustics would make it makes
really bad
community so being able to hear your
neighbors having a common meal space for
where it's just so loud you can't have a
conversation
is a great way to fail because as much
as you want to have those conversations
you can't have them
when all of the background noise is
going on and good fences make good
neighbors good acoustics make good
neighbors
nice yeah i'll go back too to the
um i think say just a lack of
self-awareness
uh be one one sort of failure mode
and i mean this kind of in the in the
general sense maybe it's maybe it's
leadership maybe it's norms and rules
and it's the community as a whole
but uh lack of self-awareness um
just kills your i guess they'll say
adaptivity
and ability to grow and flex
and a community is always kind of moving
and shifting and changing
the dynamics and self-awareness a high
degree of self-awareness
uh i think is usually required for
success over time in adapting
to things
can you break that down a little bit
more like what's your
can you give some examples of maybe
like failure modes like what do you see
happening over time
yeah i mean many of the specific things
that we've talked about
might kind of fall abstractly are you
talking about an
authoritarian leader who controls too
much like
they're doing that because they think
you know that's going to bring them
success
but you know with greater self-awareness
they realize they're sabotaging their
own community
and the lack of
conflict resolution procedures
uh you know everybody may feel better in
the moment if they push the conflict
down or if they don't address conflict
and just stuff it down
uh but uh greater self-awareness like oh
well this is
this is going to bubble up and bubble up
and boil until it it blows up
um so yeah kind of abstract but just
uh very much a thematic element in my
mind to
lots of different failure types so
one of the things that comes to mind
when you said that is being open to
criticism
um you know if if i'm in community with
folks and we're really close
we need to open ourselves up to
taking advice from one another and
taking criticism
uh in a healthy way based on how much we
trust one another
so a lack of being open to criticism
uh yeah could really move into uh you
i think you can only be so self-aware
and you can like work on it as much as
you can but ultimately
there are parts of it where you're
relying on the people around you
to help you say hey you don't realize
that you're doing this
um and yeah we really need each other
for that absolutely it's a group
collective intelligence
that self-awareness at a community level
which then goes right back to the the
safety point
of safe to fail safe to try you know is
to apply to
speech acts and relationships and
feedback and communication
uh and all of that so yeah it needs to
be um
yeah open space for honesty
transparency uh there may be norms
of acceptance and interaction
that really facilitate that and make
that a
a strong constant lived uh thing because
it's uncomfortable
um oh which reminds me i was just
thinking like oh because people coming
into the community
are going to come in with not that norm
very much the opposite
of that norm and they're going to come
in be quiet uh
not feel comfortable giving feedback as
the new you know new person
um but just the the um
so the the thing that rift off of there
for me was
um a community can fail if it um doesn't
champion
its culture and doesn't hold its culture
intentionally
such that as it grows the community the
the culture gets
uh dissipated dissolved uh regression to
norm regression to the mean
uh as more and more people come in and
bring outside culture
into the community uh intentionally
whole you know if they don't
intentionally hold that culture and
almost not indoctrinate but
you know champion and preserve and uh
grow that uh their their specific
culture then they will lose it and fail
yeah and and to add to that i really
love that hold your culture
intentionally thing
um otherwise yeah it will
it will dissipate over time i would also
add
uh you would probably fail if you had no
onboarding process
now sure if you had a closed group and
you said okay we've got these 10 people
this is it or we've got these hundred
people like this is it
uh you might not need that
but say you did
a desire to grow you have to do some
kind of teaching
some kind of onboarding process the idea
that people are just going to show up
you know especially if you have some
kind of radical group
where things are very outside the
default world
people aren't gonna intuitively know
certain things
um you may need to tell people hey
here's where
here's the medical person by the way if
you get a cut or something like here's
where you go for that
you know you're you're doing some
reinvention
of society probably and
from what i've learned um
onboarding certain people love doing it
but it's kind of um i've noticed
this is just an anecdote but i've
noticed that it's kind of exhausting for
some people
they just want to move in to the
community
and do the thing they set out to do um
onboarding oh i got to teach somebody
new how long is this going to take
is it going to take weeks for them to
get it uh
onboarding for certain personality types
they just want to be doing
the main thing it can be exhausting for
some people that's
that's what i've noticed it's definitely
making those people do the onboarding
sounds like a great way to fail
the person who really knows i don't even
know but i think also having that
um membrane that isn't permeable so that
there is only even if it's 100 people
right these hundred people we've started
it there's no
um outside there's no like
unless you're having babies be born it's
gonna end at some point in time or or
people coming in that have that have
children unless there's like a way if
you feel like you have to be part of it
because if you leave you can't come back
in there's just there's a lot of and yet
you don't want
too many people leaving at once like
right now in my community i haven't
really been there in months because of
covid
and i don't live there and there are so
many people who have left and new people
coming in i'm like wow
i even like usually it's like one new
group
person and i again have to learn their
names and that's hard and i feel bad for
them because they have to learn
everyone's name
but it's like oh there's like five or
six new
families and out of 25 units that's a
lot
juan do you have anything to add
yeah i'm not so sure when i wrote my
my article my last article about this
topic i
i stumbled about
over the world intentional community and
i wrote
unintentional community and i
felt finally by seeing this
a little bit more happy
so um
i'm not so clear about your vision
uh about this word failure or the
relation between
failure and community
in a lot of moments i saw
[Music]
failure as a tool to separate
people to punish people
to downgrade
something and this was for a purpose
and i think a community
should take care of people who
think different who try
and fail and even
if you compare this with the situation
of a kid
in a family the best thing what you can
do
as a mother or the father is giving the
child
this
[Music]
this sensation this experience
of however they are failing
they don't lose the community they don't
lose
the love they don't lose access
to the quality of life inside of the
community
so this is something
i'm thinking about
yeah maybe related to that i was
thinking
you could maybe fail by not having
consequences uh i don't know what those
consequences
would be but you know um if
you did have if you had behaviors that
were not
accepted like
you'd seems like if you didn't have
consequences for unacceptable behavior
your community would fall apart right
away because
or as soon as something happened because
you would want some kind of justice
say you know so and so with stealing
like
maybe the consequence isn't that they're
kicked out maybe it is
but if there's zero consequences for
that
then anyone who was stolen from would be
like
i'm out like this doesn't even make
sense anymore
with that not honoring trade-offs
like not seeing that there is never
like consequences come with trade-offs
both ways right if the consequences are
too much you know you're
kicked out and you're no longer part of
the group if you if you steal something
well what does stealing mean
you know if a four-year-old takes
another kid's toys you know what i mean
like
like being clear and also knowing that
there's room for growth right that maybe
you didn't know what you would do when
someone stole because you didn't think
it was going to happen and then it comes
up and you're
figuring out how to how to actually deal
with it when i think about
one of the biggest trade-offs of
community is community meetings
and it's like to make everyone's voice
heard is an exhausting process and it's
exhausting so it's like you can't have
it go on for days you can't have even go
on for hours
and you need to still have everyone be
heard you can't have some people
monopolizing and not
be dealing with the issues so having
even just naming that trade-off right is
like okay well how can we get people's
voices heard without taking up hours of
time then you can
you can own it but if you're just like
no no we have to sit and listen to
everyone
that all the people who don't want to do
that aren't being heard
right like they're silenced their need
for silence isn't being heard
can you explain what the trade-off is a
little bit more you're saying like the
trade-off for having consequences
is that you have to have
deliberations is that what you mean
sorry i was they were two different
things but if you have consequences for
something there's going to be trade-offs
right that if the consequence for
stealing is getting kicked out
that's going to be different than if the
consequence for stealing is having your
arms chopped off right like those are
very
different and so it's i i was just
because i was going off of that but more
of the consequences like the meeting
like i think about um occupy movement
and they have these beautiful
two person set or two sessions every day
and i was like oh my god these are hours
long and you didn't even attend the last
one and how do you like
continue on to the next one that there
are trade-offs there's only so much time
in a day there's only so much people we
can house there's only so much
to be able to if you just aren't even
allowing
to have those trade-offs like you know
we can do it for everyone
then it's it's a way to fail it's that
answer
daniel i mean i feel like it also would
depend on
the the weight of the situation like
if you have some kind of thing that's
like a club
and you're living in game a your
community is like some club
and so the the one thing i've seen is
sexual harassment i've seen people
kicked out of communities
for that and there's other more
forgivable things
they said hey you know now the women
here don't feel safe
like sorry but you know you'll find
somewhere else
i hope you figure that out we can't fix
you and
we have stuff we want to do so uh
now in this game a
world that person is they have their job
they're gonna be okay and they're gonna
have to like
suffer their consequences and figure
that out
in life and like deal with that
now if you're off grid if we're like
post-apocalypse
or something the then it seems like
the consequences of excommunication
like what do you throw them outside the
wall and like
sorry you know you
say it was still sexual harassment well
gosh you know you throw someone outside
the wall and
it's like good luck out there that's a
feels like a very different uh situation
so we can easily what i've seen
it sucks but you can more easily
remove someone from a community because
it's like not their livelihood at stake
is what i've pers you know my anecdote
what i've observed
but you're off grid or something
someone's getting all their food and
shelter from your community
then you'd have to deal with that in a
different way
and i think that is actually a way to
fail that um was brought up in my
community i brought it up in game b
as well was when i asked who's actually
one of the families that have now left
but
one of the families is pretty christian
it's a very integral part of who they
are
and when i asked them what what kind of
community would they want to seek if
they were to seek a new one
and he didn't answer christian community
and i was like really i'm like i just
need to circle back to this why wouldn't
you and he's like because elbow
like he's in his he's 40 now
like it's not like he's probably gonna
go through that teenage crisis of faith
but he's like what if i did then i would
lose my community and i would lose my
faith
if it was around you know at the same
time and so having it two
and having it too insulated worse every
piece of your need is met by this
community right it's where you live it's
where your
livelihood is it's where every one of
your friends and family is
then yeah that's a really high metric
both for doing something wrong and also
just for
thinking you might do something wrong
feeling like you might get kicked out
and and that is a that that can be a
a way to fail to have it you know if we
had game b and then all of a sudden you
start questioning
game b community specifically and i'll
say you started questioning wait is
gaming even a thing
is it that you then get kicked out it's
like no we actually want those people
like i can point out the other issues
and that that takes me back to the
family analogy
uh and to what extent is you know is any
given community like a family and what
are the
what are the boundaries uh and what are
the
in and out points um
the um
sorry try to try to phrase this the the
the concept of failure in terms of even
throwing around like communities failing
i've mostly been thinking about that in
in the sense of
uh the community blows up or dissolves
uh almost everyone agrees that the
community didn't work and it blows up
and everybody walks away
uh is i guess my typical kind of failure
mode that i was thinking of there
but then yeah considering the the
failure mode
of well if people uh
leave or are ejected or
bounced out of a community
in the eyes of that person perhaps the
community failed
for them and if you if you aggregate
that enough
um you know i've seen places where a
community
keeps going and doesn't dissolve
but changes in nature and you know it
loses a lot of people
a lot of people a trit out of the
community
and that mass of people say oh that
community failed
it's no longer what it once was it's no
longer fulfilling its
true mission it's been corrupted or
hijacked or whatever you know and so
that's you know
that's another definition of failure and
i suppose at some level it's
all about your perspective uh either
your perspective or just
the you start weighing the raw counts of
how many people think that it has or
hasn't failed
uh if the majority inside the community
says no this is it this is we're doing
the right thing we're keeping going on
and it doesn't include you or it doesn't
include what you want to do
uh or how you want to be in this
community well then okay is that failure
well it
depends if you're the majority of the
minority there
um yeah that's helpful a really good way
to fail
especially in an intentional community
is to not learn
from all the other people who came
before like
i'm starting like i'm starting something
completely new no one's ever done this
before
and not looking at why why did they fail
because there's been a ton of
intentional communities especially in
the 60s and 70s and what was it about it
what made them successful and what made
them
just ignore all of that and just like
nope reinvent the wheel
[Music]
yeah there but um there can be
intentional communities where
the number of people in them is actually
much smaller than the number of people
who have
passed through them uh you know who have
spent time there
and have maybe moved on for one reason
or another
uh and it's interesting to consider too
of like oh you could have this huge mass
of people on the
on the outside that okay maybe it was
useful for a time
and then they moved on or maybe not or
maybe they they would have been there
but the community wouldn't
change or grow or adapt and so they had
to move on
uh you still look at that intentional
community and if
it's holding on doing things the same
way
that it has for the last 20 or 30 years
uh
and meanwhile there's just this growing
mass of people uh that it's lost
on the outside yeah what do you how do
you judge that
and well yeah i suppose i suppose at one
point you know just
fail or not fail like is the wrong
question then to ask
it seems to me like you would have to
define
what yeah what your purpose is
and that's you know failing or not
failing your right is like connected to
some kind of metric
so it's like if you had an intentional
community
and going back to like the being versus
doing
type of thing it's like if your
community was said
we're gonna do community and we're gonna
try to
you know uh raise so much money every
year
to give away or you know we have some
kind of mission
like you could have a lot of people and
you could still fail at your mission
or if or if your community was more
about just
being and you said if we can keep six
people together
minimum you know like and keep that
going
with and not worry about the mission so
that would be more of like a we just
want to be
like those are different failure modes
uh
based on what you set out to do um if
you said
we want a community of 20 people just to
be with no mission our mission is just
to
continue to be together and you did it
for a few years and you only ever hit
12.
like then you you know you failed by
the standards that you set i i suppose
um i feel like in the game b
thing we're mostly talking about going
towards
omni-win types of
ways of navigating the world
if you're still competing with one
another or you're still
causing harm externalizing harm
like if it's game b we've got to go back
to some of those core principles i think
of
um hey you could have a mission-based
large community but if you're still
causing harm
to the environment let's say then uh i'm
not sure it's game b
anymore uh that's the thought
you know taking the larger ecosystem
into effect
not taking like the planetary ecosystem
the social one i was gonna say
getting a um like a piece of land in a
country
that it's cheaper than canada or the
united states
and yet having none of those people live
there having not no amount like not
learning the language
not being part of that country just like
yep this is a plot of land that we like
and we're gonna use it that way it would
be a good way to fail
even if you succeed
or fail fail the game b metrics even if
you have a successful community
because they're different things
yeah metrics or definitions
suppose there are a few assumptions that
maybe come with the word community
itself that most people might build into
their definition of success but
free reign i mean to you success is
whatever you define it
to be uh and thus failure as well if you
define a community
as being like a family with an absolute
commitment uh to people and
you like any you know any rupture
break then of that is is a failure
that you you lost somebody you know no
matter what their transgression
that you weren't able to stay in
relationship or
rehabilitate or restore or anything
versus um
yeah you can totally define success as
the opposite
opposite like the archipelago model of
everybody has their own little island
and you can go to whatever island you
like
uh and flip between them or whatever but
uh you know just you know
not the attachment um model
so lots of so much uh
space so much domain space out there uh
in terms of what communities can be um
so yeah successes and failures or rather
perhaps arbitrarily defined thing i
think
for me zooming in and zooming out like
is it a success for the individual
to be very different and so it's not
going to be my success in communities
not going to be someone else's success
in the community
and then the community itself right are
we sustainable are we
how is our culture how is but then
zooming out even further can there be a
bigger meta community of you know what
you're not here this is not working for
you this is not working for us but
there's other people to take you on
like to to have one community can't
accept everyone right there's like
dunbar limits and stuff but to say that
there's a bigger infrastructure of
community
that trades that that has could be even
more
successful because it's also dealing
with
humans as natural elements that that my
body forms itself every seven years but
i'm still me
i don't feel you know those cells and so
to be able to have a ever-changing
structure
community that either it goes away but
the bigger one doesn't or
it's successful maybe the bigger one
does like there's failure on
yeah i like the idea of is there a
difference between success
for the larger whole versus the
the individual important to talk about
um
i mean i have a story of when i was
doing quite a bit of volunteering
a couple years ago and i
was also seeking friendships and there
was a very
good high quality volunteering community
and we did some good work however
um it wasn't meeting my need for
friendships
and as even though i was trying
you know not for lack of trying it
wasn't
kind of built into the ethos of that
volunteering community
and i had to step away i could step back
at some point but my need for
friendships
became larger than my you know ability
and need to volunteer
um and it just wasn't meeting that need
they're still doing really good work
um but i had to adjust
my priorities uh and so that would be
like yeah this individual need hey it
wasn't taking care of dan's
uh friendship needs despite the fact
that they were doing other good things
and it still exists since they're still
doing good things
but it gets complex when you get down to
the individual
i want to mention that it's uh 10
minutes before the for the hour if we
want to kind of give
um wrapping up type
thoughts and as well as i would love to
speaking of failure
i always put out my video content like
what i'm gonna do for the next week on
sunday so there's a little bit of
of because this is on monday we don't
get as much participation because we're
not doing it a week in advance
so if we could maybe come up with some
um topics for like the next two or three
weeks
and always kind of keep it that way so
that people know two or three weeks out
and not the day
before when the topic is i think that
would be that would be helpful but
just think about wrapping up the failure
part so we can
fail the last of this
as daniel was talking i was thinking
that failing to meet
people's needs would be a great sort of
capper
uh in terms of if there's anything
that's kind of tautologically the
definition
of a failure of a community of people
come
to commune together for some reason
to get some needs met and if it fails to
meet those needs
the uber failure
me that ultimate failure is not trying
like if you're never if you want to
always like i want to live in an
intentional community and you're never
in there like you can't go through that
interpersonal work unless you're there
you can't go through that community work
unless you're there
so not trying not doing something
towards it
is the ultimate failure and the only one
i actually think is
no failure like just try and keep
honoring
moving forward
for me failure is opportunity
and i welcome failure
in a way
you mean it's not a failure if we just
keep talking about it for the rest of
our lives
come on uh
i guess uh my final thought i mean i
made a pretty good list
uh that maybe can get put into
um you know whatever gets put out from
this um
and i thought
one of the important things for me on a
last note
is fun um the community better
have some fun going on i don't last very
long
uh if that isn't celebrated it can't be
all work i really like to have fun
um we can't have people like playing
board games or doing whatever people
want to do for have fun and have other
people like looking down on them like
you should be working the whole time or
whatever like
um it's gotta be fun uh
or i'm not gonna make it
so that's all i have to say all right
i'm gonna stop the recording now